UJJWAL SHARMA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Delhi,India

+91-9643-6799-78

mr.sharma.ujjwal@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

An Engineering student pursuing B.tech and a React Native Developer having a experience of around a year working with multiple projects using expo and react native both from scratch. Constructed multiple successful projects in my internships and as a freelancer, A mentor and speaker , guiding many students. Passionate about development

EDUCATION

High School / X 2017

St. John's, Academy, Delhi / CBSE

• Secured 8.4 CGPA

Higher Secondary School / XII

St. John's, Academy, Delhi / CBSE

• Secured 71% in Non-medical with CS

Under graduation / B.tech (Pursuing)

IMS Engineering College, Ghaziabad / AKTU

• B.tech in Computer Science Engineering

2019-2023

2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer (intern)

Oct, 2020 - Nov, 2020

YLURN (WFH)

- Updated the UI of the App YLURN (Available on Playstore and Appstore).
- Used Expo for the development.
- Created re-usable components for the app.
- Worked with there Restful API's to create services in the app.
- Used libraries to create new features in the app.

Front-End Developer (intern)

Apr, 2020 - Nov, 2021

Redpositive (WFH)

- Created Cross-platform Mobile Applications From scratch.
- Worked with React Native CLI.
- Used multiple libraries such as chart kit for graphs and redux for global store.
- Given KT sessions to other interns and guided them.
- Tested in multiple devices of different screen size and verisons.
- Written clean and manegeable code along with best practice of file structure.

Front-End Developer (intern)

Andwemet (WFH)

- Built there App Andwemet from scratch.
- Integrated the backend with frontend for the all the functionalities.
- Used Figma for UI and Prototype.
- Tested the app in different scenarios.
- Created the Responsive UI. which works on all screen sizes.
- Creating re-usable components for the app.

SKILLS

React Native React JS Javascript

Git and Github CSS HTML

Node JS JSON

PROJECTS

<u>Dev Connector (social media web-app)</u>

- This web app is built on MERN stack.
- Can be used to connect developers across the web.
- · By creating profile you can add about you, experience, education, links, skills etc,
- you can even post something on feed which others can like or comment on.
- you have option to delete the things in the web app.
- · hosted on heroku.

Burger Builder

- It is built with the React and firebase.
- It is used to order burger and customize visually.
- You can signln in the app to place order and add address and see previous orders.
- firebase authentication service is used to login via email or gmail.

<u>codeujjwal (Portfolio)</u>

- Created my online portfolio named as codeujjwal.
- you can visit it by googling codeujjwal.
- Built with React and hosted on netlify.

Clones (NETFLIX, AMAZON, WHATSAPP)

- Built the Netflix UI from scratch and used IMDB api for the movies and shows images.
- Built the amazon clone with features like add to cart, login, and some more
- Built Whatsapp clone, Used the UI of Whatsapp for the chat app built on web

More Projects can be seen on my github codeujjwal

ONLINE PROFILES

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>github</u> <u>Porfolio</u>

CERTIFICATES AND HONORS

React Native Speaker

Conducted a workshop on React native, Taught and guided students on mobile app development

React JS Speaker

• Conducted a workshop on React JS, Taught and guided students for web development using react js

front end web development Speaker

• Conducted a workshop on Front-end development, Taught and guided students on front-end

React - the complete guide (Hooks, Redux, Route)

• Course by Udemy for React

JavaScript- Advanced

• Course by Udemy on Javascript

Complete front end web development

- Course by Udemy.
- covered HTML, CSS, JS

SIH internal hackathon

• Presented idea in SIH and got selected for external round after internal hackathon

EXTRAS

Freelance web Developer

- Worked for clients as a freelance developer.
- constructed 3 successful projects as a freelance developer.
- MERN stack is used in the development and hosting services of netlify and heroku

Head of the club

MIND OPTIMIZERS

- Founder and head of the club in college.
- started this club to mentor and guide students on all the domains by there seniors and mates.
- conducted 4-5 successful events in which the average participation is 100+ students.